empirestores.co.uk 2007-12-11

# Empire Stores - Privacy Policy

#### Your confidentiality and privacy

We are committed to protect your privacy. We take great care to make sure you receive the best protection possible for your personal information and any financial details that you provide. The Empire Stores website is a secure site, and any personal data we collect from you is safe from misuse.

Empire Stores seeks to ensure that it acts in accordance with its requirements as set out in the Data Protection Act 1998 and as such we will endeavour to make sure that your information is only collected and used where it is necessary to fulfill your order and . enhance your shopping experience with us. This means that …

#### Information we might need from you:

Your full name, address, date of birth, customer reference, telephone number, e-mail address, credit/debit card number, expiry date and issue number. If you enter a prize draw we need your name, address, customer number and e-mail address.

#### How we use your information:

We use the information you provide to:

  * Confirm the receipt of your order, process it and keep you informed of progress 
  * Keep you up to date with new services, facilities, special offers and promotions 
  * Enhance your shopping experience in the future by tailoring the site to meet your needs 
  * Manage your account with us
  * Administer prize draws 

As a responsible lender, we search the files of credit reference agencies who record the search and share information about you and the conduct of your account with them, other lenders and relevant third parties. We check everyone's details with fraud prevention agencies and if anyone gives us false or inaccurate information and we suspect fraud, we record this. We and other organisations use such records to make decisions about credit and all types of insurance proposals and claims for you, members of your household and those with whom you are financially linked, to prove identity, for money laundering prevention and fraud prevention.

We may also use your information, including shopping habits, to open and run your credit account, including payment recovery, debtor tracing and for our marketing. We may share your information with other organisations who may contact you for marketing purposes. If you do not wish to be contacted by third parties for these purposes, please write to us or telephone us on our Customer Services Team or send an email to [queries.empire@redcats.co.uk](mailto:queries.empire@redcats.co.uk).

We may use your email address to contact you about your account and also to inform you of our offers, products and services that maybe of interest to you. We will not pass your email address to third parties unless you have given us express permission to do so or unless it is necessary to fulfill your order or we are required to do so by law. If you do not wish us to use your email address for these purposes please write to us or telephone our Customer Services Team or send an email to [queries.empire@redcats.co.uk](mailto:queries.empire@redcats.co.uk) with "email no marketing" as the subject heading and your name and customer reference number in the message box. If you are happy to receive electronic marketing from queries.empire@redcats.co.uk but no longer wish to receive electronic marketing from third parties you may withdraw permission for third party contact at any time. Simply write to us or telephone our Customer Services Team or send an email to [queries.empire@redcats.co.uk](mailto:queries.empire@redcats.co.uk) with "email no third party marketing" as the subject heading and your name and customer reference number in the message box. We will process your request as quickly as possible. There may, however, be marketing material that is currently on its way to you which cannot be stopped. Please discard this when you receive it.

If you require details of the credit reference agencies from whom we obtain and with whom we record information about you, please write to us or telephone us on our Customer Services Team.

#### Cookies

To provide you with specially tailored information from our website and to track the effectiveness of online advertising, we, in conjunction with third party companies, may use cookies. Cookies are a piece of data that a website can send to your browser and may be then stored on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which web pages and any advertisements that may be placed on them and to track the effectiveness of our online advertising generally. They also help us to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website.   
This information helps us to improve the overall level of service we provide to you.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You do not have to accept cookies and can set up your web browser to automatically notify you when you receive a cookie, this will give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. View the [privacy policy of the third party companies](https://www.atlasdmt.co.uk/privacy/general/). [Opt out of online tracking](https://www.atlasdmt.com/privacy/opting.asp).

#### How we keep this information secure:

All the information above is transmitted securely using SSL encryption. This means that the information is sent in such a way that, in the extremely unlikely event that someone is somehow able to obtain this information, only we can decode the information to obtain your details. This is done by encrypting the data between your computer and our server. We encrypt the data using a certificate provided by a trusted third party, Verisign. Click on the logo for more details.

You can tell that the data is encrypted as the address in your browser will change from // to // and a small padlock icon will appear at the bottom of your browser window. This is your guarantee that you can send your details to us with confidence.

“We are required by the Data Protection Act 1998 to follow strict security procedures in relation to the manner in which we store and disclose information. You may be assured that we will adhere to these procedures with your personal details. We cannot, however, guarantee the security of the data disclosed online in all circumstances and will not be held responsible for any loss associated with the provision of personal information unless this is caused by the willful default or negligence of Empire Stores.”
